Jim Reisner

Software Engineer

7817 Gray Fox Dr NE Cedar Rapids, IA 52402 (319) 450-6639 jim.reisner@gmail.com

Career Summary

An accomplished Software Engineer with solid programming and problem solving skills, specializing in Object Oriented architecture, Web Development, Analysis/Design, and Relational Database design. Skilled at finding the most practical solution to a problem, resulting in successful implementations in both team and individual projects

Technical Expertise

Languages

C#, Typescript, Python, Javascript, Java

Web Technologies

React.js, ASP.NET MVC, ASP.NET WebForms, jQuery, Bootstrap, HTML, CSS

Databases

SQL Server, Oracle, MySql, CosmosDb, Entity Framework, LINQ, SSIS

Cloud & DevOps

Azure Services (Azure Container Apps, Cosmos Db (Core API), Azure Functions, Service Bus, Azure Logic Apps, DevOps), Git, AWS, Docker

Concepts

Relational Database Design, Class Design, Integration, Enterprise Architecture, Microservices, RESTful Web Services, SOLID principles, Design Patterns, Cloud (Azure and AWS), Agile

Experience

RTX, Cedar Rapids, IA- Principal Specialist, Software Development 2021 - PRESENT

- Developed new applications using React.js, TypeScript, .NET, REST API
 - Integration with enterprise applications like SAP and Dynamics CRM
- Developed a custom log scanner tool that automated the analysis of multiple log files, identifying critical keywords and providing detailed resolution suggestions from a predefined database, significantly reducing troubleshooting time and improving system reliability
- Created deployment pipelines in Azure DevOps/yaml
- Enhanced and maintained legacy applications
 - ASP.Net MVC and classic ASP

Transamerica, Cedar Rapids, IA - Lead Software Engineer

2017 - 2021

- Designed Business Rule Execution Framework for sourcing data from various administration systems, executing business rules, and landing data into consumable Data Lake
 - Improved processing time from 12 hours to 20 minutes from previous solution
 - Introduced re-use of business rules, resulting in faster implementation of end-to-end processing
 - Created .NET Framework host to handle cross-cutting concerns like logging and error handling in a consistent, efficient manner
 - Created Python system to land data into Data Lake
 - Resulted in portable solution that could be executed on multiple cloud vendors or on-premises
- Designed, developed, and implemented a task execution framework for actuarial model execution, utilizing .NET Framework executing proprietary model execution software
- Designed and implemented a Python ETL platform for querying Hadoop data and landing in various destination systems.
- Utilized dependency injection to support unit testing and growth in framework capabilities
- Lead contract staff on solution implementations
- Mentored team members on Agile development methodologies

Rockwell Collins, Cedar Rapids, IA- Senior Business Integration

Analyst

2013 - 2017

- Developed centralized web-based reporting application for Human Resources secured by HR roles
- Developed custom intranet applications based on ASP.NET MVC, jQuery and Bootstrap
- Created reusable automated data extraction from SAP system
- Mentored and shared technical knowledge with the team, specifically in enterprise development technologies

StoneRiver, Cedar Rapids, IA- Senior Programmer Analyst

2011 - 2013

- Designed, coded and tested solutions for the annual release of regulatory product
- Designed, planned, and implemented customized Team Foundation Server solutions to support Agile methodologies
- Developed Continuous Integration for multiple projects and teams utilizing CruiseControl.NET

Aegon USA Investment Management, Cedar Rapids, IA- Senior

Programmer Analyst

2005-2011

- Develop and maintain internal applications in .NET WebForms
- Standardized application code by implementing the Abstract Factory design pattern
- Developed reusable classes to retrieve data from an external third-party application
- Improved data processing by 80% through the use of SQL Server Integration Services

Personal Projects

Fretboard Magic

October 2024 - Present

- https://fretboardmagic.azurewebsites.net/
- Front end is React with Typescript hosted in Azure Web Apps, back end is .NET Core Web Api, hosted in Azure Container Apps

News Notifier

August 2024 - Present

- Utilizes Azure Container Apps, Cosmos Db (Core API), Azure Functions, Service Bus, Azure Logic Apps, Docker
- https://github.com/JimReisnerPublic/NewsNotification

EDUCATION

University of Northern Iowa - Finance

1992 - 1995

Certifications

Microsoft Certified: Azure Al Engineer Associate

Microsoft Certified: Azure Developer Associate

Microsoft Certified Solutions Developer App Builder

Microsoft Certified Professional

Developing ASP.NET MVC Applications

Microsoft Specialist

Programming in HTML 5 with JavaScript and CSS3